So the first step in the hypothesis-led approach is to define the problem.
And so when you're beginning to define the problem —
what is it that makes a good problem question?
One way to do this is to think: is it a SMART question?
Is it specific? Is it measurable?
Is it actionable? Is it relevant? And is it time-bound?
And so if we think about different problem questions —
if you think about the first
test, is it specific? You want to think about:
what is the scope of it? Is it sufficiently narrow?
Are we trying to improve the value of the company?
Or, more specifically, are we trying to grow revenue?
Measurable. This is around thinking about how we're going to quantify, or think about
the key performance indicators, to know if we've achieved our goal.
And so if you're growing revenue,
are you growing it by 10% or by 30%?
So, actionable. Is it something you can actually do?
If you say, “We want to enter a new market
and capture 10% market share” —
how are you going to do that? More specifically, what are the actions
you need to take in order to make that true?
So, relevant. Is your problem relevant
for all the stakeholders involved,
and have you aligned everybody towards those goals? So, time-bound:
what is the time horizon in which the problem is solved?
If your business is facing bankruptcy, you may only have four weeks of cash left.
In those cases, the solution set is going to be a lot different.
In other cases, you may be thinking about infrastructure over a 20-to-30-year horizon.
That's again going to lead to much different approaches to the problem.
So let's think about an example of how we can use the SMART tool to refine a problem statement —
and I'll give you an example from my life, to keep it simple.
So the problem statement could be around:
where do we want to go on vacation?
More specifically, where do my wife and I want to go on vacation? Now, that's a pretty
vague definition of the problem. So how can we improve it?
Well, let's use the SMART tool.
Is it specific enough? Well, have I thought about who's going on vacation? Am I going on vacation?
Is my wife going on vacation? Hopefully the two of us are going on vacation.
Is it measurable? Well, what do I want to achieve?
Do we want to have a fun time on our vacation, or do we want to make it
the best vacation ever? Maybe we want to make it the best vacation ever.
It's a qualitative assessment, but it's still measurable. Actionable?
Hopefully in this case it is — we're actually going to go on vacation together.
And relevant? Well, certainly for me and for my wife, it should be relevant for us.
And time-bound: specifically, when do we want to go on vacation?
Well, we may rephrase it to say: where do we want to go on vacation
to have the best vacation ever within the next four months?
And that'll then define the scope of the solution space for us.
So why is having a SMART problem statement up front so important?
It's so important because, by ensuring that your problem is SMART-ly defined,
it enables you to get to the right answer more quickly.
And so the other day I was working on a problem around:
how do we grow our revenue by a certain amount next year?
Now, initially we thought about a number of different ways we could do this.
We could hire more people and increase the size of our sales force.
We could spend more on marketing and promotions.
We could think about what was our pricing strategy, et cetera.
But as we thought about it more deeply:
what were the constraints that we were actually facing?
We realized budgets were fixed, and so spending more on marketing or hiring
more people into our sales force actually was not part of the solution set.
And so when we redefined the problem statement to say:
given the existing budget that we have,
then how do we increase our revenue by a certain amount in this coming year —
that enabled us to be much more efficient
and prioritize more effectively where we're spending our time,
and get to the right answer sooner.